Guide to the Richard Lovejoy Tuthill Papers, 1946-1968
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Richard Lovejoy Tuthill papers 1946-1968
University Archives, Duke University
Tuthill, Richard Lovejoy, 1911-.
0.5 Linear Feet 350 Items
Richard Lovejoy Tuthill was Professor of Economic Geography and University Registrar at Duke University.
This collection contains correspondence, reference material, and notes on the local, state, and national organizations.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Richard Lovejoy Tuthill Papers were created from the records of the Office of the Registrar.
Biographical Note
Richard Lovejoy Tuthill was Professor of Economic Geography from 1953-1980, when he retired as Professor Emeritus. Additionally, he was appointed the first University Registrar in 1953 by President A. Hollis Edens, a post he served until 1969. He was a Fellow of the American Geographical Society of New York and one of the founding members of North Carolina Geographical Society.
Collection Overview
This collection contains correspondence, reference material, and notes on the local, state, and national organizations Richard L. Tuthill belonged to and/or interacted with, along with material concerning his non-Registrar-related activities at Duke University. These papers were separated from the records of the Office of the Registrar. For further information on Tuthill and his duties as Registrar, please see that collection. The bulk of this material centers on geography and education. Included are folders from the Association of American Geographers and the 1955 Conference on Teaching the Social Studies. Tuthill appears to have shown particular interest in the value of television as an educational tool. The collection ranges in date from 1946-1968.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Tuthill, Richard Lovejoy, 1911-.
Duke University. Office of the University Registrar.
Related Material
Records of the Office of the Registrar, 1853-; particularly Subject files, series 1 (1946-69)
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Association of American Geographers -- Southeast division, 1954-1961 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Harm J. Blij -- visit to Duke University, 1967
  - Dr. Harm J. Blij -- visit to Duke University, 1967
  - Conference on Teaching the Social Studies, 1955
  - Educational Television, 1965
  - Extramural activities, circa 1965
  - Geography conference, 1956
  - Good Friday service, 1965
  - Inauguration -- President William C. Friday (UNC system), 1957
  - Inauguration -- President A.N. Whiting (NC College in Durham), 1968
  - Joint Program in History and the Social-Behavioral Sciences proposal, no date
  - National Aviation Education Council -- Committee on Aviation and Geography, 1946-1951
  - North Carolina In-School Television Program, 1956-1967
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee for Duke University, 1966
  - Sermon material, 1961
  - Television Education Conference, Spring 1965
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Publishing Company, 1953-1955
  - United States Air Force aerobatics team -- The Thunderbirds, circa 1960